John Patrick Miller

Front-End Web Developer

legendzing@gmail.com

Summary

I have more than a decade's worth of management experience in retail and convenience store environments. The convenience industry is fast-paced and the stores I managed were high-volume establishments. My leadership abilities soared in these environments, but I wanted to find a career in a creative field. In 2012, I took improv and writing classes at Chicago's Second City and began working as a freelance writer. By 2014, I recognized the need to expand into web development with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery and its other libraries and frameworks. I'm excited to have found a challenging and rewarding career in user interface development, front-end web development and user experience design. I value community enrichment and hope to use my skills to elevate others along the way.

Projects

Neighborhood Map March 2015 to April 2015

Members: John Patrick Miller

The neighborhood map incorporates Google Maps and FourSquare APIs to highlight interesting locations in my town.

Skills & Expertise

Front-end Development

HTML5

CSS

JavaScript

iQuery

KnockoutJS

AngularJS

JasmineJS

Photoshop

User Experience

User Interface Design

Leadership

Management

Marketing

Training

Customer Service

Sales

Content Management

HTML

Retail

Sales Management

Merchandising

Inventory Management

Customer Satisfaction

Negotiation

Social Networking

Microsoft Office

Microsoft Excel

PowerPoint

Visual Merchandising

Profit

Store Management

Team Building

Teamwork

Budgets

Facebook

Microsoft Word

Hiring

Inventory Control

Strategic Planning

P&L Management

Coaching

Process Scheduler

Sales Operations

Recruiting

Operations Management

Customer Retention

Pricing

Purchasing

Employee Training

Experience

Web Developer at Web Developer

May 2015 - Present (2 months)

I design responsive websites with the user experience in mind. I want to make all user interfaces easy to navigate, quick to understand and so welcoming that your target audience will come back again and again. I'm knowledgeable in HTML, CSS, javaScript, jQuery, AngularJS, KnockoutJS and JasmineJS. I practice Lund's Usability Maxims and Object-Oriented Programming. My portfolio is open for all to view at https://github.com/TheChronicMonster.

Executive Content Director at Urban Gaming Elite

August 2014 - Present (11 months)

Urban Gaming Elite is a work of passion. It is a fairly new media and entertainment startup based out of Milwaukee with a mission to create a community of inclusive video game developers and enthusiasts in the Midwest. I work closely with the founder, Alex Schwartz, to deliver quality articles and fun entertainment pieces revolving around the video game industry. Together, Alex and I have hired freelance writers to help promote the site and produce content for our viewers. I have met with community organizers in our region to discover opportunities for partnerships, and to find mutually beneficial ways to promote our missions and expand market share in the locality. I also edit articles, use an FTP client to upload freelancer articles, edit images, use vanilla html to post articles on our server and use technology to telecommute and correlate work with Alex and our freelance writers.

Freelance Writer at Freelance Writer

February 2013 - June 2015 (2 years 5 months)

My experience as a freelance writer began with www.nouveaudating.com and led me to work with the talented Lara Philips in Chicago. I primarily write neighborhood blog posts describing the neighborhoods and suburbs of Chicago. I have also composed several blogs focusing on homeownership and housekeeping. In all, I have written more than 200 published blog posts.

Independent Contractor at Independent Contractor

January 2012 - December 2014 (3 years)

I've been self employed since returning to Wisconsin in early 2012. I've worked with distribution centers to move mail, checks, automotive parts, and tractor equipment to retailers and banks in the greater Rockford and Chicago regions. I've formed professional relationships with clients over the years and have developed a reputation for friendly, fast, and punctual service.

Personal Banker at Wells Fargo Bank

August 2010 - December 2011 (1 year 5 months)

Worked with a talented team of bankers and tellers to provide the best service possible for our customers. I helped small businesses open new accounts and apply for credit. Customers relied on me for honest and competent advice. Knowledge of company products made me a successful team member that was able to consistently meet monthly sales expectations.

General Manager at E-Z Mart

February 2009 - August 2010 (1 year 7 months)

The good people at EZ-Mart hired me directly as a manager based on my resume. They trained me in store operations and put me over their newest store. I managed the clerks and a small kitchen staff and learned the ropes of the C-store industry. After a few months the executives moved me to a higher volume store that had been neglected. I cleaned up the premises with the help of my

staff and also found time to help other managers with their duties. Within a year I was promoted to a newly constructed store on I-30. I managed inventory, trained assistants to become managers of their own stores, and consistently broke sales records.

Principal Administrator at Lighthouse Christian Academy

August 2007 - December 2008 (1 year 5 months)

I administrated a small private school with approximately 30 students and six teachers. The school was located in a very depressed neighborhood and many of my students were minorities who needed help in reading, writing, and math. My staff and I worked very hard to educate the students and "bring them up to speed" in the critical subjects. I also taught math and led physical education, collected tuition, led weekly teacher meetings, ordered and purchased learning materials, and helped manage food inventory.

General Manager at Unclaimed Furniture

January 2001 - May 2007 (6 years 5 months)

My career at Unclaimed Furniture began as a part time delivery assistant. I learned all of the basic skills of furniture assembly and delivery and worked my way into a full time position. Before long I was selling merchandise on the showroom until my boss, the owner, told me to go to Office Depot and print up business cards that read "General Manager." I managed the storefront, provided excellent service to all of my customers, helped order inventory, kept sales records, and created sales promotions to raise revenues in slower months.

Certifications

Intro to HTML and CSS

Udacity December 2014

JavaScript Basics

Udacity January 2015

Front-End Web Developer Nanodegree

Udacity May 2015

shaping-up-with-angular-js

Code School May 2015

Education

The Second City

Improvisational Acting, Comedic Writing, 2012 - 2013 Activities and Societies: improv and comedic writing

Texarkana College

Associate Degree, Business Marketing Activities and Societies: Phi Theta Kappa

Texas A&M University

Bachelor, Applied Arts & Sciences

Activities and Societies: Student Leadership Development Program

Udacity

Front-End Web Development Nanodegree, Web Page, Digital/Multimedia and Information Resources

Design

Activities and Societies: Udacity Guide

Volunteer Experience

Board Member & Tutor at The Literacy Connection

April 2014 - Present (1 year 3 months)

I work with a young man to help him improve his Math skills in order to complete his GED.

Volunteer Instructor at Junior Achievement

2011 - Present (4 years)

Worked with Junior Achievement to teach High School students the importance of budgeting, saving, and completing their high school education.

Tutor at Texarkana Baptist Orphanage

2007 - Present (8 years)

I helped young students understand their math homework, helped them prepare for test, and celebrated their successes.

Languages

English (Native or bilingual proficiency)

Courses

Front-End Web Development Nanodegree,

Web Page, Digital/Multimedia and Information

Resources Design

Udacity

| Website Performance Optimization | ud884 |
|----------------------------------|-------|
| Intro to AJAX | ud110 |
| JavaScript Design Patterns | ud989 |
| Intro to jQuery | ud245 |
| JavaScript Basics | ud804 |
| JavaScript Testing | ud549 |
| Object-Oriented JavaScript | ud015 |
| Intro to HTML and CSS | ud304 |
| | |

John Patrick Miller

Front-End Web Developer

legendzing@gmail.com



Contact John Patrick on LinkedIn